<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vincent Peng Portfolio on Vincent Peng</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vincent Peng Portfolio on Vincent Peng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 11:15:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Music Genre Classification</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>I started this project out of interest in music analytics, and the data sets can be found on Kaggle. Here is a picture of the data set that contains 22 features and 26752 samples.  Data Set   For my analysis I decided to focus on 9 features, which includes popularity, danceability, energy, acousticness, instrumentalness, loudness, liveness, speechiness, and valence. Most of these features are described on Spotify&amp;rsquo;s audio analysis page, but all the variables range from 0 to 1 and are based on Spotify&amp;rsquo;s algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Activity Recognition Project</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>This project is about using data collected from a Samsung smartphone to classify whether the human was sitting, standing, laying, walking, or walking upstairs/downstairs. For our features we used the 3-axial linear acceleration and angular velocity collected by the accelerometer and gyroscope, which are built in the phone. These features were sampled at 50Hz or 50 measurements per second. Since the raw data is quite noisy, the raw data has been filtered and extracted to 561 features that characterize the measurement in time and frequency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cushing Syndrome: Discriminant analysis and Baye&#39;s Classifier</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>One of the main topics in machine learning is classification, so this project was about comparing Linear Discriminant Analysis(LDA), Quadratic discriminant analysis(QDA), and the optimal Baye&amp;rsquo;s Classifier. The first plot shows three samples of multivariate Gaussian distributions, the LDA boundary(magenta), and the Baye&amp;rsquo;s classifier boundary(black). The second part of the project was to predict the diagnosis of Cushing Syndrome using concentrations of steroid metabolites, specifically tetrahydrocortisone and pregnanetriol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regression Analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The Regression Analysis is a project I worked on in my machine learning course, where I wanted to compare models with different levels of complexities with a true model using randomly generated noisy data . The first graph shows the true model(black curve) and the generated noisy points in green. The rest of the plot shows the different levels of complexities using regression analysis. Another part of the project was to look the bias variance trade off for the model, and a good way to show this theory is to compare a group of 100 samples from each level of complexity which is shown on the second plot using the Colin Mallows statistic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comet Analysis</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>This project was about modeling the solar system and comets in python to analyze comet-earth collision probabilities within a 10 year time frame. The first step of the project was to create a projectile function to predict where the asteroids will land, and we used Halley&amp;rsquo;s Comet to validate the function. The plot above confirms that the physics works out by showing the known orbit(O) and the calculated trajectory(T) for Halley&amp;rsquo;s Comet have the same path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://example.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Feel free to contact me through any of these platforms
   Platform URL     LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/vincent-peng-154611214   Email: vpeng1@jhu.edu    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
